莉西的故事 第一季 第七集
斯科特 你棒呆了
Scott, you're amazing!
专程来见你
Came out just to see you!
这真是最棒的一天了
The best day of my life!
这和《遗迹》里的那支一模一样 我为你做的
It's exactly like the one in Relics. I made it for you.
是根魔杖
It's a magic wand.
谢谢
Thanks.
我不需要签名
I don't want an autograph.
我只想让你知道 你让我的人生变得不同
I just want you to know you changed my life.
是你改变了我 是你
You did it. You!
好的 谢谢 我们可以进去了
Okay, thanks, we can go inside now.
兰登先生 听起来你状态一点都不好
Mr. Landon, you really don't sound good at all.
不 我没事 真的
No, I'm... I'm fine. Really.
好吧
Okay.
上一个能在化妆间门上
You know the last time, uh, a writer had a star
挂星星的作家还是
on his dressing room door, it's...
是啊 梦想成真
Yep. Living the dream.
赞助这次活动的书店有一名店员
Um, the staff from the bookstore who's sponsoring the event
非常想来见你一面 可以吗
would really love to come up and say hello, if that's okay.
没问题 不过我需要几分钟
Yeah, that's fine. Just give me a few minutes
先把状态调整好 好吗
to get myself together, okay?
当然
Absolutely.
不是吧
Oh, boy.
该死
Fuck.
兰登先生
Mr. Landon?
我也不想催您 但大家都在等着您呢
I hate to rush you, but they're ready for you.
兰登先生 您听得到我说话吗
Mr. Landon, can you hear me?
兰登先生
Mr. Landon?
您还好吗
Are you okay?
兰登先生 听得到我说话吗
Mr. Landon, can you hear me?
您没事吧
Are you okay?
兰登先生
Mr. Landon!
Mr. Landon.
兰登先生 开开门
Mr. Landon, open the door.
您还好吗
Are you okay?
兰登先生
Mr. Landon?
- 兰登先生 - 我在这
- Mr. Landon! - Hey.
我出来后卫生间门被锁上了
The, uh, bathroom door locked behind me.
麻烦你请保安把门打开
Could you get security to open it
然后帮我把手机取出来 可以吗
and grab my phone?
没问题
Sure.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
开始吧
Let's do it.
今晚 我们邀请到的这位作家
Tonight, we have with us a writer
不需要我过多介绍了
who truly needs no introduction.
他从事写作多年 著有十本畅销书籍
After many years and ten best-selling books,
已成为文学界的偶像
he has become a literary icon.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
让我们用热烈的掌声欢迎斯科特・兰登
please give a big welcome to Scott Landon.
很高兴站在这里 活着真好
Good to be here and great to be alive or what?
标志上说此池塘禁止游泳
The sign says no swimming in the pool!
我们有什么要对它说的吗 露营者们
And what do we say to that, campers?
跳进去就是了
Dive right in!
那标志是谁弄的
Who put that sign up?
搞笑的条子们
The fun police!
在朗读新书之前
Before I read to you from my new book...
我想先讲讲
... I thought I'd talk a
一本小说是怎样写成的
little about how a novel comes into being.
抱歉
Sorry.
别着急 斯科特
Take your time, Scott.
怎么回事
What's happening?
每一本
Every...
小说
... novel...
都是作者与故事之间的
is a... A struggle between the writer and the...
都是作者和故事的博弈
A struggle between the writer and the story.
而作者 至少就我来说
And the writer, well, at least this one...
总是在试图...
always tries...
掌控节奏
to hold on to keep control.
故事...
The story...
该死
Fuck.
- 天啊 - 你还好吗
- Oh. Oh, God. - You all right?
缓一缓吧 老兄
Take a break, man.
- 他手上的是血吗 - 怎么回事啊
- Is that blood on his hand? - What's going on?
- 给他点水 - 那是血吗
- Get some water. - Is that blood?
麻烦你们...
Can somebody...
给我妻子打个电话...
call my w-wife...
在场有医生吗
Is there a doctor in the house?
喂 老公 现在几点
Hey, babe. What time is it?
打电话的不是您的丈夫 兰登夫人
This isn't your husband, Mrs. Landon.
我是詹特森医生 这里是哈德逊山纪念医院
It's Dr. Jantzen at Hudson Hill Memorial Hospital.
您的丈夫今晚被送进医院
Your husband was admitted tonight.
什么 发生什么了
What? What... What happened?
他在柱廊剧场
He was at The Colonnade Theater,
进行朗读会途中昏倒
scheduled to give a reading and he collapsed.
等等 他 他 他还好吗
Wait a minute. Wait. Is... Is... Is he all right?
兰登夫人 我建议您
Mrs. Landon, I think you
尽快赶来医院
should get here as soon as you possibly can.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 兰登夫人 我很抱歉 - 他人在哪
- Mrs. Landon, I'm so sorry about... - Where is he?
詹特森医生应该正在里面等您
I believe a Dr. Jantzen is waiting for you inside.
他在车上咳嗽得很严重
He was coughing in the car and it was not light.
后来我去化妆间找他时
And then I came to see him in his dressing room...
- 好了 谢谢你 - 兰登夫人
- Okay, thank you. - Mrs. Landon.
- 你好 - 请跟我来
- Yeah. - Come with me, please.
非常感谢 谢谢你
Thank you so much. Thank you.
莫里斯医生 请拨打112 莫里斯医生
Dr. Morris, dial 112, please. Dr. Morris.
- 詹特森医生 - 您好 兰登夫人
- Dr. Jantzen. - Hello, Mrs. Landon.
您比我预计的来得早 太好了
You got here much faster than I expected. That's good.
- 他人在哪 - 在楼上
- Where is he? - One floor up.
在场没有医生见过旧伤复发
None of us here have ever seen old wounds reopen.
他的肺 体液
His lungs, the water...
可以基本确定病原是病毒
The root cause is almost certainly viral,
但具体是什么病毒现在还无从得知
but as of now we have no idea what virus that might be,
能确定的只有病毒的感染速度极快
but only that it's taken hold with incredible speed.
他要求摘掉呼吸器
He requested to be taken off the ventilator.
什么 为什么
What? Why?
他想和您说话
He wants to talk to you.
情况有多糟
How bad is it?
高烧41摄氏度 且伴有器官衰竭
He's running a fever of 106 degrees, and he's in organ failure.
我很遗憾 兰登夫人
I'm sorry, Mrs. Landon.
他在等您
He's holding on for you.
我来了
Hey.
- 莉西 - 我在
- Lisey? - Yeah.
我好热
I'm so hot.
太热了
It's so hot.
有冰块吗
Is there ice?
帮我们拿点冰块 麻烦给我们点冰块好吗
Can we have some ice? Can we have some ice, please?
好的 没问题
Yes, of course.
好了 咱们走
Okay. All right, let's go.
咱们去池塘
Let's go to the pool.
只要你需要 就爬过去
Just crawl there if you have to.
那个高个男孩
Long boy.
高个男孩怎么了
What about the long boy?
把路挡住了
Blocking the path.
比树还高
Higher than the trees.
我无路可走
No way around.
不 不 发生什么了
No, no, no. No. What happened?
到底 发生什么了
What... What happened?
那是
Something from...
很久之前的事
... A long time ago.
从我还是个孩子时
From when I was a kid.
是保罗
Something from Paul.
保罗
From... From Paul?
爸爸
Oh, Daddy!
爸爸救我
Daddy, help!
保罗发病了
Paul's got the bad!
爸爸 爸爸 救我
Daddy! Daddy, help!
保罗又发作了 爸爸
Paul's got the bad! Daddy!
你被感染了
You're infected.
他把我割开了
He cut me.
自从...
Ever since...
这些年以来...
all these years...
有些事已经...
something has been...
这是保罗弄的吗
This is from Paul?
我从机场候机室
I went to Boo'ya Moon...
去了布雅月...
from the airport lounge.
我又去了一次
I went again.
那里仍被封锁着
It's still blocked.
没法进入池塘
No way to the pool.
不 试试
No, try. Try.
试试 再试试
Try. Try again. Try again.
你和我 莉西
You and me, Lisey.
你和我
You and me.
天呐
Oh, my God.
我多么爱你
How I loved you.
我爱你 别说了
I love you. I love you. Stop.
别说话...
Don't talk. Just...
- 别说了 缓口气 - 我曾迷失在黑暗中
- Stop talking. Save your breath... - I was lost in the dark.
我曾...
I was...
迷失在黑暗中
lost in the dark.
你发现了我
And you found me.
你抱紧我
You held me.
不 不
No. No, no, no.
No. No.
宝贝
Oh, baby.
不
No.
- 不... - 宝贝
- No, no, no, no, no, no. - Baby.
不要死
Don't go.
宝贝
Babyluv.
不 不 不
No, no, no, no, no, no.
不 别离开
No, don't go, don't go.
别离开
Don't go.
不 别离开
No, don't go.
亲爱的 我不知道该怎么活下去
I don't know how to be this way, hon.
我不知道要怎么想
I don't know how to think it.
你会知道的 你...
You would know. You...
你会知道
You would know.
你说过 心口一致
You said saying is knowing.
那... 我要说些什么... 难道要我说
So... So what do I... what do I say? Do I say...
说你过世了吗
Do I say you kicked the bucket?
要我说...
Do I say...
你已经离我而去了吗
you popped off?
你是不是已经撒手尘寰了
Are you eating a dirt sandwich?
你是不是驾鹤西去了
Are you riding the mystery train?
你是不是两腿一蹬
Did you bite the big one?
与世长辞了
Pop your clogs?
去世了
Peg out?
不 魂归天国呢
No. Uh... bought the farm?
我不知道 到底要我怎么说呢
I don't know. What do I say?
要怎么说 我不知道
What is it? I don't know.
我不知道要怎么想
I don't know how to think it.
没有希望
No light.
没有活力
No spark.
没有希望
No light.
没有活力
No spark.
没有希望 没有活力
No light. No spark.
没有希望
No light.
没有活力
No spark.
总部 二号巡逻车 位置在糖顶路
Base, this is Two out on Sugartop Road.
你不是值班结束了
Thought you were 10-10.
是的 但我想再去兰登家巡逻一次
Yeah.Thought I'd take another run past the Landon place.
我感觉不妙 查完就下班
I just have a funny feeling. Then I'll be 10-10.
收到 完毕
Copy that. Out.
莉西
Lisey.
嘿
Hey.
那是什么
What is that?
这是根曲棍球棒 上面有亲笔签名
Oh, it's a hockey stick. A signed hockey stick.
放在她丈夫的运动橱柜里
It was in her hubby's sports cupboard.
不过我看不出是谁签的
Can't make out the name, though.
我觉得那些曲棍球员肯定是文盲
I think hockey players must be illiterate.
那是帕特里斯・伯杰龙
It's Patrice Bergeron,
要是你把那球棒弄坏了
and if anything happens to it,
马特不会放过你
Matt's gonna kill you.
那我们有什么计划
So, what's the plan?
我擒住他 只要他倒地上
I'm gonna tackle him, and then once he's down,
你们就出来压住他 然后我带他去布雅月
you can pile on and then I'm gonna take him to Boo'ya...
你要带他去那个地方
You're gonna take him to that place that you went.
布雅月吗
Boo'ya Moon?
天呐
Jesus.
很好 我希望那混蛋被雨浇透
Good. I hope the asshole gets soaked.
阿曼达 你知道为何你是双界人
Amanda, do you know why you were a double?
还有那块带图案的编织毛毯
And the afghan too?
它同时出现在两界
It was in both places at once.
抱歉 你说什么
I'm sorry, the what?
好妈妈送给我们做结婚礼物的编织毛毯
The afghan that Good Ma gave us as a wedding present.
斯科特很喜欢
Scott loved it.
你嫁的男人真奇怪
You married a very strange man.
斯科特也是双界人
Scott was a double too.
他大概...八年前就是个双界人了
He was... He was a double about eight years ago.
他从没跟我说过双界人的事
He never said anything about doubles, at least to me.
他知道怎么过去 莉西
He knew how to get there, Lisey,
但除此之外 他知道的事也不多
but beyond that, I don't think he knew very much.
不 他知道池塘
No, but he knew about the pool,
因为过去他演讲时
because he used to talk
经常提到池塘
about it all the time when he gave lectures.
我们都喝过的池塘的水
The pool where we all went down to drink.
我以为那只是个比喻
I thought it was a metaphor.
现在你知道真相了
Now you know better.
你记得什么
What do you remember?
我记得那里景色很美...
I remember it was beautiful...
但又很可怕
and terrible.
后来我再也不想去那里
And I never want to go back there again.
好的 以后你就和我们待在这里
Good, then you're gonna stay here with us.
好的 我尽量
Okay, I'll try, I'll try.
那长凳上那些人呢
What about the people on the benches?
被裹着的那些人是谁
The ones that are wrapped up. Who are they?
不知道 我不想谈那些被裹着的人
I don't know. I don't want to talk about the shrouded ones.
但你觉得他们是谁
But what do you think they are?
- 我不想谈这事 - 好的
- I don't want to talk about that. - Okay.
好吧 抱歉
Okay, I'm sorry.
不必这么激动吧
Don't get your panties in a bunch...
如果你不谈那些事的话...
Don't get your panties in a bunch
我就不会激动
if you don't... talk about things that I don't...
别吵了 你们俩 停
Stop. Okay, both of you, stop it.
你们藏起来 进浴室里 把门关上
Just... Just go. Go hide. Go into the bathroom and shut the door.
得让他进来的时候 以为我是一个人
He needs to think that I'm alone when he comes.
我...我确实记得一件事
I do... I do remember one thing.
不是布雅月的事
Not from Boo'ya Moon.
而是在这个世界 斯科特对我说的事
From... From here. Something Scott said.
就是上次...
Just after the, uh...
我割伤自己
Last time that I... that I cut myself,
就是他死之前
you know, when I went dark,
我陷入疯狂的时候
before he died.
他讲了个故事 他说是关于莉西的故事
Something about a story. It was Lisey's story, he said.
他从没给你写过书 对吧
He never dedicated a book to you, did he?
没有 我叫他别写
No. I asked him not to.
为什么
Why?
因为他出名后 一切都变了
Because everything changed once he became famous.
我们变得世界瞩目
You know, the world came in.
婚姻得有私人空间 不能完全公开
You have to have a private part to a marriage, a secret part.
否则的话...
And if we hadn't have had that...
我们的婚姻肯定葬送在名利中
we never would have survived all this rich and famous shit.
那个故事讲了什么
What was the story about?
他好像没说过
I don't think he said.
即使他讲过 我也忘了 抱歉
If he did, I don't remember. I'm sorry.
你真有办法对付杜利吗
Do you really have a plan for dealing with Dooley?
是的
I do.
不过我们需要个暗号 以防我需要帮助
But we need a code word, in case I need you.
安全词 像是玩虐恋
Oh, a safe word. Yeah, like S&M.
什么 你和查理喜欢玩虐恋吗
What? Were you and Charlie into S&M?
天呐 当然不是 他所谓的
Oh, God, no. His idea of
刺激就是穿着袜子上床
bedroom excitement was leaving his socks on.
什么词 莉西
What word, Lisey?
"绿地"
"Greenlawn."
你们会听见我和他谈话...
So, you're gonna hear me talking to him...
等等 等等 你为什么要和他谈
Wait, wait, wait. Why are you talking to him?
因为我必须和他谈 我得离他很近
Because I need to talk to him. I need to be close to him.
我必须得离他很近
I have to be close to him.
除非听见"绿地"这个词不然不要出来
Don't come out unless you hear "Greenlawn."
然后你们抓住他
And then you can tackle him.
- 这是B计划吗 - 对 这是B计划
- That's plan B? - Yeah. That's plan B.
好吧 B计划很烂 A计划完全没逻辑
Okay, plan B sucks. And plan A makes absolutely no sense.
这计划感觉并没有仔细想清楚 莉西
Really doesn't sound like it was thoroughly thought out, Lisey.
有时候你得让故事自己书写
Sometimes you have to let the story tell itself.
- 我求你了 - 不 不
- Oh, I am begging you. - No, no.
- 我求你别胡说 - 拜托 不
- I am begging you to stop this bullshit. - Come on, no.
有时候你得让故事书写自己
Sometimes you have to let the story tell itself.
你邀请了一个疯子进你的家
You invited a maniac, a fucking lunatic into your house!
别喊了 她知道她...
Stop yelling. She knows what she...
就去藏起来吧
Just go hide.
- 她没有计划 - 进卫生间 关上门
- She has no plan! - Get into the bathroom. Shut the door.
我该怎么办
What am I supposed to do?
该死
Fuck.
进卫生间
Get into the bathroom.
我要上厕所
I have to pee.
不行
No.
莉西
Lisey?
什么
What?
我要上厕所
I have to pee.
你就在厕所啊
Well, you're in the right place for it.
- 达拉不让我上 - 闭嘴
- Darla won't let me. - Shut it.
你是个成年女人了 你能忍住
You're a grown woman, you can hold it.
安静 你们两个 安静
Be quiet. Both of you, be quiet.
杜利先生
Mr. Dooley.
我知道你在
I know you're here.
我在这里 夫人
I'm right here, Missus.
你看不见我 但我能看见你
You can't see me, but I can see you.
你骗人
You're lying.
如果我骗人 那我就要死了 小姐
Well, if I'm lying, I'm dying, miss.
你手里是什么 是枪吗
What's that in your hand? Is that a gun?
为什么我会有枪
Why would I have a gun?
我们是来交谈的 不是吗
We're here to make an exchange, right?
我今晚和你还有其他事情要做
Well, I got other business with you tonight.
你是来杀我的 是不是
You're here to kill me, aren't you?
你躲在那个东西的后面 那个灯塔
You know, that thing you're hiding behind, that lighthouse,
那是你丈夫的
that was your husband's.
那是斯科特・兰登最大的奖品
That was Scott Landon's biggest prize.
写下的最伟大的书卖出七十五万本
750,000 books sold for his greatest novel ever written,
《海边遗民的女儿》
Coaster's Daughter.
我好奇一件事情 吉姆
I'm curious about something, Jim.
我是说... 我希望你不介意我叫你吉姆
I mean, I... I hope you don't mind if I call you Jim.
我感觉我们现在是朋友了
I feel like we're friends now.
我就当你同意了
I'll take that as a yes.
当斯科特谈到写作时
There was something that Scott talked about
他说过一件事
when he talked about writing.
他说他是从狄更斯那里学的
He said he learned it from Dickens.
我不是来谈写作的 夫人
Well, I didn't come here to talk about writing, Missus.
什么
What?
你算什么书迷啊
What kind of a camper are you?
你都不愿谈最喜欢的作者
You don't want to talk about your favorite writer.
"让我振作起来 斯科蒂"
"Beam me up, Scotty."
- "爱的责任" - 我是先知
- "Duty of love." - I'm a prophet.
"爱的责任" 那是你最喜欢的
"The duty of love," That's your favorite.
我是最伟大的书迷
I'm the greatest camper there ever was,
我来这里是要确保
and I came here to make sure
把斯科特・兰登的作品与世界分享
that Scott Landon's works are shared with the entire world.
斯科特说小说中的每个角色都得用两次
Scott said that every character in a novel had to be used twice.
但是我们的故事里
But there's one character
有一个角色只用了一次
in our story that's been used only once.
那就是... 科尔
And that's... that's Cole.
在田纳西的那个大学开枪打中我丈夫的人
The man who shot my husband at that university in Tennessee.
你是田纳西的 是不是
Hey, but you're from Tennessee. Right?
- 来自志愿者州的吉姆・丹迪 - 闭嘴
- A Jim Dandy from the volunteer state? - Shut up.
你认识科尔
You knew Cole.
那个开枪打我丈夫的人 是吧
The man who shot my husband. Right?
你在精神病院认识的他 疯人院
You know him from the mental hospital, from the asylum.
- 闭嘴 - 是啊
- Shut up! - Yeah.
斯科特和我以前会经常谈你们这样的人
Scott and I used to talk about guys like you. All the time.
我们叫你们"深空牛仔"
We called you "Deep space cowboys."
你们大多都很无害 是不是
Most of you are harmless. Right?
但你和科尔不是的
But you and Cole aren't.
闭嘴 闭嘴 闭嘴
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
几个深空牛仔
Just a couple of deep space cowboys
坐在精神病院
sitting around the mental hospital
谈论着斯科特・兰登属于谁
talking about who Scott Landon belonged to.
- 你不是英雄 - 闭嘴
- And you're not a hero. - Shut up!
- 你不是英雄 - 闭嘴 闭嘴 闭嘴
- You're not a hero. - Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
你只是一个疯狂的粉丝
You're just a crazy fan!
闭嘴 闭嘴 闭嘴
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
你喜欢我的灯塔吗
You like my lighthouse?
那不是你的灯塔
That's not your lighthouse!
那是大家的灯塔 那是斯科特・兰登的奖品
That is everyone's lighthouse! That is Scott Landon's prize!
你是我的奖品
You're my prize.
绿地 绿地 绿地
Greenlawn! Greenlawn! Greenlawn!
嘿
Hey!
你该死的 该死的混蛋 去死吧
You fucker, you motherfucker! Fucking die!
你敢动她 混蛋
Don't you mess with her, motherfucker!
过来这里 抓我啊
Hey! Come over here! Get me!
莉西
Lisey!
该死
Oh, fuck!
去死 去死 去死
Die, die, die!
滚开
Fuck off!
你个混蛋 把他弄下去 弄下去
You fucking asshole! Get him off me! Get him off!
杀了他
Kill him.
尊重
Respect!
没有老婆
No wife!
尊重
Respect!
你想对我做什么 夫人
What are you trying to do to me, Missus?
总是得担心动机
Always have to worry about motivation.
小心巧合
Beware of coincidence.
解释情况
Explain situations.
都是胡说八道
Which is bullshit!
因为现实生活不是这样的
Because life doesn't work that way!
你和谁在一起
Who are you with?
从没有人
Never did.
- 现实是条狗 - 你和谁在一起
- Reality is a fucking dog. - Who are you with?
不知为何穿越了一千五百英里
That somehow travels 1,500 miles
在三年后 回到了家
and ends up at home, three years later.
你就是个老婆
You are just the wife!
你不是艺术家
You are not an artist!
现实是拉尔夫
Reality is Ralph.
你不是诗人
You are not a poet!
现实是拉尔夫
Reality is Ralph.
你只是和他睡了
You were just sleeping with him!
你去哪了
Where'd you go?
你真恶心
You're disgusting!
- 我知道你在这里 - 别自私
- I know you're here. - Don't be selfish!
- 为什么不分享 - 我知道
- Why won't you share? - I know.
和世界分享
Share with the world!
过来
Come here.
你在哪儿
Where are you?
告诉你一件事 夫人
Tell you one thing, Missus.
你不会回家了
You are not going home.
你是他最大的错误
You were the greatest mistake he ever made!
过来
Come on!
你是个自大的婊子
You're an ignorant bitch!
你害怕了吗
Are you afraid?
去你的 我是灯塔
Fuck you! I am the lighthouse.
- 过来 过来 - 我是先知
- Come on, come on. - I am a prophet.
来啊 来啊 过来
Come on! Come here! Come here!
帮帮我
Help me.
你在这里啊
There you are.